[Music]
business channels and magazines to know
about
business leaders little did we imagine
that we would one day
be spending a saturday with one
amazing leader and received his wisdom
on a critical topic like insurance
resilience
in a rapidly changing crona virus world
our sincere gratitude to the eminent
guest of today
mr parker saskatchewan who is the
managing director
and ceo at iclci longboard
he's a name to reckon with for his
critical leadership positions
in diverse business areas in the icici
group
and we are very grateful that he agreed
to deliver this special talk
under the leadership dogs 2020 series on
re-imagining insurance industry
post-government 19.
i'm very happy to welcome some of the
friends of our
biblical insurance fraternity who have
always supported us
in our mission um i am very delighted to
welcome
mr p d banerjee whose independent
director royal sundaram general
insurance company tonight
and he was formerly chairman managing
director the overwhelming insurance
company limited
as well as insurance mumbai
he's also joined by mr
who is currently on the board of court
of mahindra general insurance
as an independent director and one of
his
latest monograph on insurance governance
for world's largest democracy where
bimbic was also a
knowledge partner it lays down a
complete
insurance governance framework and it
has been received
very well by the insurance regulator as
well as the concerned ministries
in india
and managing director of state aig
general insurance company liberty
it's also an honor to have with us one
of our member of the board of governors
which is
thank you at the outset i would like to
invite our director dr harivan's chapter
baby team
uh he has been leading the institute
in a very futuristic way and to the kids
back
when he decided that bimtech should
launch a bdcm
program in insurance i'm sure
that it was really good for our
institute and today we are being led by
so many ceos and leaders of that
industry
our students gain faculty gain and
on behalf of all the chairpersons
means students and faculty members
i extend my warm welcome to all of you
and hand
over the session to our director for his
welcome address
thank you uh professor
our esteem uh
chief guest who is going to address
our students faculty research scholars
uh mr
our board member mr saket ketan
my senior colleague
my colleagues from the insurance program
are dr abhijit professor morose
and also our young colleague
monika nipple so it's a great occasion
for us
to offer to our students
not only of insurance programs but
from other programs also this
leadership talks
series for the current year
already we could have
another award from the industry doctor
a few months back he's a group executive
president and chief economist
with adida group renowned economist of
the country
so for the last couple of years we have
been invited inviting
senior leaders from the industry and
also from
the public life of the country
and the purpose is that students should
learn
not only from books or from classroom
interaction with their faculty they
should also learn from the life
lives and achievements of the corporate
leaders
social leaders and we are
thankful to mr bhargava
for sharing time today on this weekend
i have picked up some of the very
important loving for our students from
his profile
that he started his career with icici
group
in 1992 completed
more than 28 years
he's the ceo for icici lombard general
insurance company limited
for last one decade
he has been involved with various
businesses of icici
group but particularly i would like to
mention
the international banking group of icici
bank
he built its presence in 15 countries
within four years
and there is a case
on this big achievement at harvard
business school it is being taught
in various business schools of the world
so i think insurance industry
is very important for india
future destiny it is important
for the global economy particularly
after covert 19
a pandemic which has never
felt and seen for last hundred years
there is a lot of talk about how to
manage future risk
coming arising out of disasters
pandemics and also
many other types of risk
associated with human lives
i would like to
just submit that in our vision
it has been mentioned that we are
developing ethical leaders
with entrepreneurial and global mindset
is striving for sustainability and
inclusive growth
so it is a vision we are trying to
practice in
our life and in our
practice we are teaching our students
that they should also try they should
also strive to become ethical leaders
with entrepreneurial and global mindset
they should
strive for sustainability and inclusive
growth in their future life
it is true that in the very beginning
they will not get
leadership opportunities but definitely
some of them a few of them may like
become
leaders like mr bhargavdas gupta
and they will have to learn how
mr das gupta rose this
high position by working tirelessly
following the vision of the company
where he has been working for last so
many years
so over to saloni and i
welcome our speaker for today mr
bhargavdas gupta and i also welcome
our other esteemed guests whose names i
have mentioned this is a big occasion
and definitely it will be recorded
in our our
newsletter as well as other publications
thank you
thank you so much sir and you rightly
said in the vision we
talk about developing global thought
leaders and ethical leaders
and what a wonderful testimonial we have
today with us sir
um when the course had started you must
have thought about nurturing such
leaders and you just mentioned that you
know one day we will soon have our own
ceos
at least um you know we have these
success stories and one
such testimonial has joined us today i
feel very delighted and very proud to
welcome
vedic and i'm calling her by her first
name because she
is a student of pgdm insurance
and from the 2010-12 batch she was a
gold medalist so that's a testimonial of
the kind of course we are running here
and that's the story walk the talk
today she's joined us because she
is going to tell us how she has gained
and how she has
reached the position of associate vice
president in reinsurance
in icici lombard under the leadership
of mr parker so i thought that
the right opportunity for hideisha to
actually
introduce our eminent speaker of the day
in the leadership
of series 2020. welcome vishal thank you
so much for
joining please let us know uh
your journey with mr dasgupta and
handing it over to you welcome thank you
thanks a lot miss saloni good evening
everyone good evening sir
indeed it is a great pleasure for me and
a big honor for me
to introduce my ceo mr bhargav dasgupta
at the institute where i have spent two
great years
bhargav holds pg dba from indian
institute of management bangalore
and a be mechanical degree from jadavpur
university
bhargav is a career icici man
having begun his stint at the earth
while icsa limited in 1992.
within the group he has held many
critical leadership positions
including project finance corporate
banking and treasury
e-commerce strategy international
banking and life insurance
he was ceo icsi echonet limited
where he was responsible for private
equity investments
in the internet communication and
technology sectors
incubation of new internet related
business
and e-initiatives of various business
units of icicide group
as also mentioned by chatham he
set up he has set up the international
banking group of icsa bank
and built its presence in 15 countries
within four
years which is a case study at harvard
business school
prior to his current role at icsl
at isis lombard he was the executive
director of icc prudential life
insurance
in 2009 bhargav joined icsa lombard as
md and ceo
with him at the helm the company has
moved from strength to strength
and has consolidated its market share in
its preferred segment
and became the first non-life insurance
company to get listed on stock exchange
bhargav has also consistently pushed for
using technology
to provide innovative solutions which
has resulted in the company
introducing many first in the industry
such as virtual inspection and motor
bots which issue quotations for
corporate customers
and use of natural language processing
for to reduce health claim
approval time in past five years
that i have worked with the organization
i have experienced
first hand how these solutions not only
help solve customer problems
but also make day-to-day lives easier
for us as employees
his another great contribution has been
building a culture where employees are
empowered to take decisions
it is a testament to his leadership that
when the covet 19 pandemic
hit the country and the economy earlier
this year
the company was not only able to move
seamlessly to
working from home but also able to come
up with new solutions for customers
both corporate and individuals he is
currently
the chairman fiki's insurance insurance
and pension committee
and is the director on board of bfsi
sector skill council of india
he is also a member of various iidi
appointed committees
like health insurance forum in john's
advising committee
for a man who does so much he also
somehow manages the time to read
and keep himself updated on the
developments across the world
indeed his bookshelf which we can see on
many calls
and even currently we can see is an
object of envy amongst many of us
he is also an avid runner having taken
part in many international marathons
i request mr bhagavatas gupta for his
insights
on reimagining insurance industry
postcode 19.
thank you
thank you thank you thank you
professor sinha and uh professor vedi
for giving me this opportunity
honestly it's a very very uh pleasant
surprise
to uh see that vidisha is also here
you know she's uh she's an outstanding
uh young leader
in the in the organization you know
we've worked reasonably closely because
she's in reinsurance
uh and you know given the criticality of
the function there is a lot of times
that we spend together
uh you know i can uh you know look at
her and see the quality of
students that you have in bim tech and i
didn't expect to see her here
so it's a it's a great uh pleasure to
see you uh
thank you sir thanks a lot indeed it is
my pleasure
to be associated with the company and
the college and being able to
uh relate both of them thank you thank
you
so uh you know i i won't you know waste
too much time
uh talking about uh you know anything
else but
what i'll do is i'll uh kind of give a
overview of how we think uh things are
going to shape
up and you know the whole idea was to
give an overview and then
probably have a more uh interactive
session
uh that's what i discussed with uh
professor
raj and i thought that would be more
helpful uh for all of you
and honestly speaking in this panel
today in this forum today we have some
uh you know leaders that i have looked
up to in the insurance
space some outstanding uh thought
leaders in the industry
and some people that i've worked closely
with so it will be
an absolute honor to share some of our
insights
i would love to others also join in if
they feel that they have
something to add to what i'm saying so
uh
let's just move to where what you want
to cover today uh the impact of covet on
insurance
you know covet has really affected all
of us
you know you know who would have
imagined that we would be sitting uh
in our respective homes talking to each
other uh in a on a platform
that we had ever never imagined uh
possible even three years back
and it's something that has become
routine for us but
honestly this pandemic is first and
foremost a human tragedy
and it's something that has deeply
affected humanity
you know and the economy at large and
the stakes for
individuals businesses workers the
economy overall
is really really extreme
where will this head i mean honestly
speaking no one knows
how this the course of this pandemic
will uh you know run through over the
next you know six months over 18 months
will
depend greatly on the vaccine that all
of us are eagerly awaiting uh the
arrival of
but let's be real even if we get a
vaccine
we will have take a lot of time to uh
actually you know administer it to to
all the
uh you know a countrymen across the
across the country that itself will take
uh you know months if not years
so in effect uh we have to mentally be
prepared to live with this
uh pandemic for at least the foreseeable
future
the impact as i said on this of this
pandemic is not just on
uh on health and all of our lives
i think the biggest impact has been also
in the economy
and one of the things that uh we debated
a lot
in the beginning of this pandemic when
everything got shut down
uh is would this recovery whenever
things recover
would it be v-shaped or which means a
sharp recovery will it be a u-shaped
recovery with a little bit of time
and then it'll pick up or will it be an
l-shaped recovery you know it will be
flat for a long time and then we'll pick
up
i think increasingly what most people
are beginning to realize
is that it looks like a k-shaped
recovery
what i mean by a k-shaped recovery is
that there are some parts of the economy
which is
recovering faster maybe the organized
sector
of the economy maybe some of the better
well-managed companies
are gaining market share at this point
in time
but unfortunately uh there are a lot of
people who
probably suffering a lot in certain
sectors of economy of course
certain services sectors uh travel
tourism to give an example
but also a certain uh part of our
countrymen i mean
the particularly the uh the urban core
so it's a k-shape recovery it's
recovering fast some part of it and some
part of it not
and we have to think about the impact of
this pandemic and the economic impact
uh in terms of how much this impact will
be over a period
to decide how much it will shape you
know where the industry is going to go
and one of the views that in the
beginning a lot of people uh had
was that it will be a temporary impact
you know yes we will have some
lockdown for some time uh you know
sometime later we'll
open up people will come back to work
and
the world will begin to look like it was
uh sometime later
and the view was that typically you know
human beings kind of
get used to some of these changes and
move on in life so
the change will be temporary and in the
long term the change may not be very
very impactful
our belief right from beginning was that
it would not be so i think this is
a transformational event at a
civilizational level
uh what i mean by that is that if you
look at some world events in the in the
recent past
uh let's say 9 11 something that
affected our industry a lot
uh had a huge impact on the travel
industry travel and tourism industry in
terms of the way
the industry was organized from a safety
perspective from terrorism perspective
and it changed the way we you know took
flights and and we got used to it
but 9 11 was a sharp localized event at
a point in time
the current pandemic is something that
is uh impacting
many many more people over a long period
of time
and at a deeply personal level i think
across the world everyone has got impact
now you know all psychologists will tell
you that impacts of events of the these
nature
leave a very very marked impact on uh on
human beings
and our belief is this will be one such
which means this will actually change
potentially geopolitics it will
potentially change the world order
it definitely will change economics uh
it will change the way we
conduct ourselves so there will be
societal change there is clearly going
to be technological things
and in that context we have to think
about
what is what it does to insurance
now in terms of looking at our industry
our industry is clearly in bang in the
center of this pandemic because we are a
risk industry
and when we think about how this is
going to change our lives
in the future first thing that we have
to think about is
how does it affect our consumers because
at the end of the day we are in
uh businesses of providing risk
solutions to our customers
and how they change because of this
event
will determine how we have to adapt as
an industry
and i think the first thing that comes
to my mind is that
this event will have a big impact
in terms of awareness and increased need
for
personal insurance you know this is not
something that
any one of us wished on anyone else but
fact remains that
because of this event there is a greater
awareness of the need for protection
particularly for life insurance and
health insurance
and there's been a lot of surveys done
by reinsurance companies you know swissy
has done something rj has done something
across asia all research and all surveys
throughout the same
feedback that there is a lot of increase
in personal uh
insurance demand in in the minds of
consumers
so that's one change that we think will
happen the second change that we are
experiencing as we speak
is a changed expectation from
customers in how they consume services
clearly there are two types of customers
if i just keep it simple
one who are not as discoverers and you
know who are willing to go out and
step out and go into crowded areas don't
worry about the risk
and there's a large part of customers
who are still worried about
you know contracting the disease and at
least that segment of customer is
expecting contactless service
when it comes to claims or policy
processing across
board most customers are also expecting
that
you become you as an insurance company
become a second
source of trusted advice uh it's not
just
it's not good enough to solve for a
claim when it happens but advise me on
my wellness
on my prevention uh advise me on where i
should
go to when it comes to taking the
treatment and you know be a
more of a trusted partner beyond just
paying claims
so that is to me two big changes that we
are seeing people are expecting
you know contactless digitized services
and people are looking forward to
someone
uh you know it could be insurance it
could be someone else to provide them
advice that they can trust when it comes
to health care and personal protection
and of course you know as an
organization as an insurance industry we
have to see how we can provide that uh
that support the third thing that we are
seeing coming from customers
is you know as the new risks are coming
through
there is clearly a demand for new
product constructs
i talked about health in terms of in
health specifically as an industry
we had traditionally been providing only
ipd solutions
that is if you you know go to a hospital
stay there for 24 hours
we pay for the claims that's not what
customers
are only concerned about when they come
when they have uh you know when they
look at their healthcare
what customers are looking at is can we
provide a comprehensive healthcare
solution
to their needs and can we also provide
them
solution which reduces the risk of
further infection when they go to a
hospital so for example
can we think of providing outpatient
cover where you go to a
you know doctor not in a hospital but
you know your your family doctor
get treated for something that doesn't
need hospitalization
pay for the pharmacy bills pay for the
diagnostic uh you know
the test labs your labs it said lab
tests etc
and uh potentially do that on a on a
seamless paperless cashless process so
that it's convenient for me
they're also saying that you know i
would love to take teleconsulting why do
i have to go to a visitor hospital at
this point in time because i don't want
to take
a risk of going to a hospital so can you
provide me tele consulting
can you provide home-based care you know
for small
ailments small diseases you don't really
need to go to a hospital
and in fact if you provide me care in my
home uh the
the risk of you know infection comes
down and i'm more at comfort
it's really this is you know based on
one process that we've done about 28
of indian response respondents are
asking for some of these
incremental features to their uh to
their policy and
honestly again they're looking for more
digitized more personalized cover
based on uh you know specifically
customized solution
driven by wellness platforms that
they're willing to uh you know kind of
join in so one of the things that we are
seeing is people are willing to share
their personal data with you
if you are able to provide you know use
the data to provide them better products
and
better services so when it comes to
customized health insurance
using the data that they're willing to
share when they're coming on your
platform
for wellness solutions if you can give
them some benefits they're happy for
uh you know for uh you're happy to
provide that data
so that's one transformation that is
possibly coming through in the health
insurance space similarly as more people
are working from home
the demand for cyber is increasing uh
you know
as organizations we could manage uh
perimeter security as we call it when
everyone comes into our network within
the organization
we create firewalls and boundaries etc
and we manage it now as everyone goes to
their homes and
[Music]
from them to think about how you manage
the cyber risk and and this is something
that is clearly
uh you know increasing day on day and we
have to provide solutions to protect
uh you know corporates and retail
employees from cyber
and that's why you know is emerging as a
bigger opportunity
similarly for home india unfortunately
the home insurance penetration is very
low
but as you're working from home with
assets of the corporate
uh you know beer to laptop or meet some
other you know devices that you have
which are corporate property and you're
working from home uh
again the demand for home insurance is
broadening beyond what traditionally was
home insurance
now there are possibilities of provide
cover providing covers which
take care of uh your personal assets as
also corporate assets that's
uh you know another opportunity retail
level at a corporate level
uh i think you know all of you who
students of insurance have seen uh the
kind of uh debate that has uh developed
in the west
in terms of business interaction covers
in india that do it never happened
because we never had any non-damage bi
covers
uh prevalent in india that clearly is a
need
of the hour now how we price it how we
underwrite
the risk etc is something that we have
to solve for but clearly there is a
big opportunity for a non-damage bi risk
particularly for smes
in events like this and one thing that
is being talked about a lot
is uh solving for the pandemic problem
and
the pandemic risk is a challenging risk
to solve for
insurers because the the tail risk is
very high
so the solution that people are talking
about is pandemic pools
which limit the tail risk for commercial
insurance with some kind of a public
you know private private solution at
least in the initial period until the
pool gets built up
and that will help uh you know create
more uh resilience
and certainty for businesses if you can
provide these solutions
so clearly there is a a big change in
terms of the customer
demand on um a need service and demand
on you know and products that is coming
through
and last trend that we are seeing is
there is a bit of a flight to safety
uh so one of the things that we think
will will happen is some of the
better and stronger companies will uh
you know benefit
for some time uh in terms of customer
reference shifting to some of these
companies that's a trend that we are
seeing across industry
so what is the imperative for insurers
what do we need to do to address
this need of of consumers
and another thing that i want to talk
about when i'm talking about corporates
is that our
insurance companies is that this
pandemic has told us
or taught us that there are there is
another way of working
which could potentially be positive in
certain aspects
and necessary in another but it's an
opportunity to
look at for the future uh so one of the
things that is
clearly very clear to all of us is that
all organizations have to become much
more digitized connected and
agile i mean we have to work together in
a
uh in a remote you know a manner where
people are sitting
sitting and working from homes but
become but remain as
uh collaborative as connected uh
as fast in terms of finding solutions to
uh to
customer needs and as as effective as if
we were sitting together
that means there's a lot of
transformation that organizations have
had to go through
both in terms of internal processes the
technology that we
put in but also the way we work and this
is probably a
change that is here for the long term
this is not just a temporary change in
the lockdown period
you've probably read and seen that
globally a lot of technical technology
companies are saying this is the way we
will continue to work
our view is that this is actually an
opportunity to do many things
when you think about your employee base
you can give
a more flexible way of working someone
could decide to work two days at home
and three days in
in office when things become normal
someone could decide that i want to work
from my hometown
in you know let's say indoor though my
you know based offices
is in mumbai and if the organization
allows me to do that i would be happy
so there are these opportunities that
are opening up
for which organizations need to reorient
the way they you know
they go about doing their day-to-day
operations so that's one thing
in terms of staying more connected uh
allowing more remote working and
yet becoming more agile to solve
customer needs that are changing very
very rapidly
the second uh you know imperative for
insurance organizations and in fact any
service organization is
to implement digital at scale i mean
there are enough whatsapp jokes
that have been going around saying that
who drove your technology
your digital transformation whether the
cto or the ceo are poor
and honestly the answer is probably all
three for most companies
what govit has done is uh uh scale this
or or you know you know make this change
come true much faster than what it would
have otherwise
all organizations have realized that we
need to become
much more automated and digitized to be
able to uh compete
now when you talk about digitization it
is not just about selling policies
it is also about how we how we as an
organization do everything that we do
as an organization we need it for policy
sourcing be it for normal policy
servicing
it for claim servicing be it the way we
operate
as an entity within ourselves across
with our agents and our
employees all of that needs to be
digitized in some way or form
and this honestly is
you know not only an imperative for
growth it's possibly an imperative for
survival if you don't do this
as an organization you may not remain uh
viable in the long term so this is the
second imperative for insurance
companies as an
as i said for any company third is
for our industry there is an opportunity
to modernize our digital
distribution channels what i mean by
that is that
there is a lot of debate that most
policy sourcing will shift to online
channels
we don't believe that some of some
customers will you know will definitely
shift to digital channels
and as a personality digital channel
sourcing may increase and would increase
but india is a country where we don't
believe
all the customer base will shift to
digital channels we believe that
customers would still want to have
interaction with their trusted agent
will need some broker to give them
advice
we'll need to go to uh you know maybe a
dealer to buy an insurance policy
will go to a bank to buy a policy so you
have to
think of being a company which provides
all means of accessing your your
products and services
across various distribution channels
however
the distribution channel can make be
made much more digitized
and become a more of a hybrid channel
where
there is a lot of physical touch but
equally there is a lot of
technology making the process very
convenient smooth and low cost
uh you know for for you so this would
mean completely
for example from agency side it could
mean complete the online recruitment
management
uh training you know using uh using
videos which we've been doing in
these times but this could be the way
for the future uh similarly using
uh you know rpa tools the robotic
process automation tools
advanced analytics to you know help
themselves you know sell more policies
uh you know completely digital app-based
solution platform accelerated platforms
so these are things that will that will
become absolutely essential uh for
companies uh
you know in the short term forget
you know medium and long term fourth
thing that we are seeing is becoming
even more possible
is the point that i made that a lot of
customers are expecting insurance
companies to become their trusted
risk management partners it's not just
good enough to pay claims
but can you help me with my risk so when
it comes to
individual customers can you help me
with wellness and
other solutions so that i don't fall
sick similarly for corporates can you
analyze my claims data
and tell me how i prevent a claim from
happening uh
can you look at my marine transit uh you
know losses and tell me how i prevent a
loss
going in and today there are a lot of
technologies this is not just to do with
covid
as a company we've been doing this for
almost six seven years now
but i think cobit will accelerate this
this change
with these technologies like iot
telematics or using drones
you can actually uh you know solve for
this risk management solution
or corporates much better than what you
could have in the past
and last point that i'll make for
corporates is our insurance companies is
that
i think this is a time which where you
have to become very very cautious and
careful
because of the uncertainty in the market
and you have to be
very sensitive sensible about how you
manage your business
and one of the things that you have to
do is really optimize your cost
again you're bringing more efficiency in
operations while you invest in
training people you know you're building
up your employee base and making them
more competent
and building distribution but all the
unnecessary
you know flab in the system has to be
tightly controlled because these are
difficult
so these five would be in my mind uh
imperatives for insurance company
if they want to sustain and do well uh
in the long term
but i'll end with one point that uh you
know personally
has been very you know close to my heart
and i think
this has been a wake up call this event
has been a wake-up call for
uh corporate sector in general not just
insurance
uh i talked about the fact that we've
had a k-shaped recovery
and i wanted to talk about that because
i wanted to highlight the point that
you know and in this crisis uh there is
still a large
population of people who are still
suffering and i think one of the things
that
uh corporates across the world are
beginning to realize
is that for 50 years we've probably
changed you know
you you've you know we've gone after and
changed the false god
uh the view was that the only role and
responsible the corporates had was
uh shareholder capitalism your only
responsibility was to
ensure that your shareholder made money
that's an important objective
but that's not the only objective i
think increasingly
uh corporates and at least a good
corporates are beginning to understand
that you need to uh think about all
possible stakeholders meet your
employees
meet your customers meet your
distributors
be it society in enlarge what are you
doing as an organization
which is helping society in a positive
manner
rather than just you know focus on
making money for your shareholders as i
said making money for a shareholder is
absolutely right
because if you don't do that you don't
exist but
you have to do it in a manner that is
positive for society in
in its entirety and that's something
that
i think the events that has happened in
the in the last you know few months
uh particularly let's say what happened
in the migrant crisis i think that
uh realization has probably got uh
further enhanced
at this period i hope that we as uh you
know corporates don't forget this moment
and remain true to uh stakeholder
capitalism rather than shareholder
capitalism i personally have a big
believer in capitalism rather than
socialism
so i don't want to message something
which means that we are talking about
something else
but the way we organize ourselves uh has
to keep in mind has to be in a manner
that keeps in mind
society at large and as an insurance
company we have a big role to play in
that
in that sense where as i said we can do
a lot more
in terms of helping our customers in a
meaningfully positive way
again using some of the technology uh
tools that are coming uh you know
becoming available to do that well
and that's something that uh at least a
nice day longer we
keep trying to do so that's what i want
to cover and
you know as a overview and then take
questions from
uh thank you
thank you so much sir that was very
enriching and i'm sure
everyone has a lot to take from your
session today
uh at this point of time i hand over the
session
to the chairperson of insurance program
dr abhijit chattarat who is himself for
chatham-shura as well as uh he's well
known
in the field of research and training
and consultancies
in this industry and academy so
uh welcome abigail sir i hand over this
session with the qa
and um let's let's invite and uh
many many of these comments are already
here
uh thank you so much professor salani
and welcome back sir
uh uh i start with the lighter wind in
the sense that
sir you spend quality time in banking
the life insurance and
for the from 2009 in general insurance
as the captain of the industry which
role did you like the most the one in
bank or one in life insurance or in
general insurance you know when i
uh when i uh was moved when i moved from
the bank
uh initially i thought my first love
will always be in banking
having you know started my career in
banking and it's it's natural right your
first job is something that you
hold very close to your heart and
honestly
there's a lot that i got from banking
and i found it very exciting
particularly my last
setting of the international map but but
um a few months into general insurance
particularly i found this sector very
very exciting and the fact that i've
you know i've been happy to do this job
for 11 years is probably a testimony
to that fact i think one other thing and
i keep saying this and you know since
you have your students here
one of the things that i realized coming
in general insurance
and particularly as an engineer is that
this is
a sector with even financial services
where you can really learn a lot and you
can
leverage your technology uh you know our
engineering skills to some extent
more than any other part of financial
services and i'll give a couple of
examples
this is a this is the sector which is
really a sector where you need to go
deep into the underlying
underlying drivers of an industry so let
me give you a couple of examples so if
you're looking at a
auto insurance you really need to
understand
an automobile much better than if you
were doing auto financing
when you give a loan you have to
understand the credit if you do
insurance
you have to understand the risk but also
understand when you are
handling claims uh a complete
perspective on the auto including car
part
car parts and you know how to repair
them at that level so if you are
interested in knowledge at a second
level this industry is fascinating the
other thing is that
this industry can actually deploy
technology to do a lot of things which
is very very
interesting i talked about some of these
rpa tools or iot or telematics etc
that's very unique to gi so gi is an
exciting space i i just love this
industry
thank you so much what about the loss of
to the banking industry was definitely
again to
of general insurance industry hope we
will continue to
lead the industry in days to come having
a serious question
now the next normal requires
comprehensive
and very ambitious response across
five areas one is
how do you resolve to come out from this
crisis
resilience everybody is talking about
and then the most important your talk
was
you revolved about re-imagination and
reform
one of the issues that you also touched
during this discussion was
mitigating the risk for your employees
that was the big biggest challenge that
you faced
and then you had to also ensure
operational
continuity how did you really you said
that's now that
one can work from indoor if he wants to
work from indoor
his headquarters maybe in mumbai or some
other places
so how did you look at it and how did
you come out of it
what was the result before you when the
kovic
before befall on everybody in the
industry
yeah so i guess all of us you know kind
of were put in the deeper end of the
pool so we had to learn to swim right
thankfully as a company we had been
investing in a lot of uh
you know digital tools we most of our
lot of our internal
uh workflow systems are on the cloud we
had uh you know microsoft teams as a
company which were already using that in
certain parts of the organization were
using
so we had the tools but honestly
speaking all of us were not i mean
all our meetings were physical maybe
some video conferencing we never use
teams for our team meetings for example
we had to get used to at leadership
level all of us had to get used to that
but i think the first principle that we
said was that uh employee safety is most
primary at this point in time that was
very that was very clear in our mind and
we kind of started
preparing for some kind of a bc
you know visiting uh about two to three
weeks before the lockdown happened and
that was
you know thankfully we kind of a bit
early in that we were beginning to see
what was happening in europe and we were
worrying about it so we started
preparing for it
so when we moved into london a lot of
things had already been
put in place uh but what we're now
seeing is that uh
when we are thinking about this way of
working going ahead
uh we see this as potentially you know
and positive opportunity in the sense
that we can give a choice to employ as i
said
uh we've done certain things and we will
continue to do some more things for our
employees so one of the things that we
did was
uh give data cards or broadband
connectivity to
you know specific uh people who didn't
have some of those things
um we've giving you know let's say
laptops to everyone we give
headsets to people who need headsets we
are now
uh you know this quarter we will uh
start giving out
ergonomic chairs to employees desks to
employees who are one zip for their home
so basically giving them the basic tools
that
people would get to have at home and we
are
yet now not kind of at least in the
bigger cities we have
large offices where normally come we are
not asking people to come to office if
they're
you know productive from home they're
productive and i think what i talked
about in terms of uh
you know the opportunity these are
opportunities that we think will evolve
uh you know i think geography is history
uh people can sit in
uh as i said in indore and work for a
bombay based company and even a
us-based company uh so that's something
that we should
take advantage
what of of i.t preparedness was for
because the critical services
were needed to be delivered through it
platform
uh or was the industrial ready for this
kind of item preparedness or
all of a sudden uh everybody was found
in a tz and
never knew how to come out of it so
again president
i guess is different across different
companies so as you know first april is
a big month for
corporate business in india and if you
look at smes
smes are also uh you know it is a
similar boat
so one of the things when we went into
lockdown in march we were worried about
uh i mean a lot of people would buddy
about it but what we had been doing
uh even before this is preparing the
organization for a digital
uh approach in any case it was not
something that we got it got triggered
because of this
so we had for example uh digital
platforms through which you can source
policies
and you know even as i said for
corporate policies
we had digital processes so you can you
know even before this covered event
an agent in uh you know in in ripple
on saturday evening would decide to
issue a policy
where no human being would underwrite
the policy it was a
robotic process automation tool that we
had built um
and using that tool for almost most of
our you know
products some products we couldn't but
most of our products was uh
so we could do that so in the month of
april for sme policies where it's not
uh retail simple standardized policies
each are customized
you know you know difficult uh you know
complicated uh
policies uh ninety percent of our
policies were issued
digitally uh come to claim service we
had
uh started a virtual inspection process
which is
someone you you know customer or a
garage can use their
mobile phone and get a survey done where
our survey doesn't need to travel to the
location they can do it from the comfort
of their office
now just move that office location to
their home location everything else
continues
so we had 100 percent of claims
inspections in the first month
a month and a half for auto and
happening on the
inspect uh app as we call it and
similarly there are
you know other things that so i think as
an organization if you kind of
even believed in digitization you had to
ramp it up for anyone who hadn't it must
have been a big struggle
right so we need one study and we found
that health has all of a sudden become
the new priority
for most of the it's it's going to come
out in a book that
bim tech will publish in a couple of
months time
now greatest challenge that i or anybody
in the industry
foresee is that this this
renewed awareness how this
renewed awareness can be sustained in
days to come
it's a big opportunity area people are
looking at health insurance and other
form of insurance health insurance and
life insurance in particular
this is an opportunity area to build on
this opportunity how are you going to
sustain this
opportunity will it translate in more
penetrations
more uh take for insurance product in
days to come
again our view is the the answer is yes
as i said event of this nature is not
something that people forget
uh in a short time uh people i think
that you know i was
talking to someone a friend of mine
whose parents stay in
a place in mp a small town in mp
there was and he was talking about how
his local milk guy
was explaining to him the importance of
insurance and i the question that i
asked him is that
does that person think that insurance is
like an atm card you
pay a premium and you definitely take
the money out he said no he understands
the concept that
you don't get a claim every year if you
fall sick you get the kill
that's music to our years right in
insurance so i think there is a
realization of importance of
insurance and i don't think it's going
to go away
what we have to do as an industry is to
really solve for true needs of customers
if we are if your product is useful
people will buy it and when i say true
needs as i keep saying that insurance is
not just
about claimed settlement it is also
really helping customers with their
health needs
which means the continuum of care which
means uh
wellness preventive advisory and all of
that and if you can do all of you know
that all of that and i'm sure the health
insurance industry will move in that
direction
uh my sense is that the demand will of
course this year has been a spike
it may not sustain at this level next
year but i think there's a step change
in the overall
demand for health insurance in the long
term it's not a short term
and that reminds me of what we normally
customer engagement and today people are
talking in terms of digital customer
engagement
is that going to happen
according to you so let me give you an
example of from our
experience right from icc member so we
had launched uh
an app called uh i'll icy lombard take
care i'll take care
so that is a kind of i'll take
where we provided all of those so we
provided an opd policy
we did it for you know b2b customers
corporate customers
uh where you could do a telehealth
consulting service
you could after the telehealth
consulting the doctor would give you the
prescription the prescription we are
tied up with the pharmacies the
drugs would be delivered at home um
after that if you wanted to go to a
diagnostic center for tests that was
covered in the network
all of that completely paperless
digitized and we had uh
you know advisors for uh you know you
know
you know basically expert advice that
was available
we had a kind of a concierge service if
you needed to go to a hospital we gave
you
choices and and some suggestions are
what is good what is bad we had second
opinion and all of these pieces were
there
uh what in this period when uh the
in the last six months uh since we had
launched it last year the number of
downloads very small this uh six months
the downloads have grown
uh roughly about seven times in this
period the number of daily consultants
consultation that people are doing is
increasing month and month
so you know it's not as what will happen
i think some of this is already
happening
may not be across the industry but my
sense is that companies that take the
lead in doing this more
will we believe benefit in the long term
one question coming from a student he
wants to understand
how can the insurance industry revamp
its operations by embracing
blockchain technology in claim
processing and reducing over dependence
on tpa
so as a company we don't we have our own
internal team
we don't use a third party administrator
but
i think the question is a very very good
question it's not just from a tpa
perspective
even for us uh blockchain technology
could
help us in terms of streamlining the
process with hospitals
and making it a better service
experience for customers and what
happens with customers today
uh when they the day they wait you know
one discharge
we get the bills from the hospital maybe
an hour before
the discharge time and we process it and
give it back
and then there's some two and four and
the customer is waiting and at times it
takes a couple of hours for the customer
to get discharged
it's not a pleasant experience now if
you can actually use blockchain uh
you know as the customer is being uh
treated
on a real-time basis some of this
information could flow to us
we could actually keep the files
processed and when the customer is
discharged it is a smooth process
without any
checking at that point in time so there
are a lot of possibilities that are
that are there but obviously it's a you
know you know you need
two hands to clap so as an industry and
the hospitals you have to come together
and do some of these things
to make it happen opportunity is
definitely there
a blockchain with the service provider
that's hospital is understandable
but what about the blockchain across all
the couriers all the insurance providers
fraud is one area which is adopting all
kind of business
so fraud elimination the blockchain has
a big role
in fraud elimination absolutely
absolutely in fact one of the things
that we've done uh
in with some of the insurers in bombay
at least because we are all
you know some of us in bombay kind of
managed to get it together
is on um on the motor side we are doing
exactly that as a pilot
uh we've experimented with that and it
actually works well
uh on prevention of fraud and prevention
of let's say
uh miss declaration on claims experience
in the past last year you know
one of the things that we see is people
don't declare the previous year's claim
to get in
you know no claim bonus yes so those
things can be eliminated so those are
things that are
we've experimented it's not scaled up uh
obviously
we can do a lot better as an industry
another question that i'm getting is
what are we are experiencing resurgent
of virus in u.s
and europe european countries what is
your outlook for the next six months
is it going to impact risk profile and
hence risk management
of insurance industry you know any
expert who's predicted anything to
this virus has proved to be you know a
false expert right so i don't want to
say that i know what is going to happen
with this virus
i think what we've seen is in terms of
the claims data we've seen
we think the numbers seem to have peaked
in september and october seems to be
roughly kind of flat slightly lower
but we also worry about a second spike
because of festive uh season
that we are going through at this point
in time um we've seen what happened in
kerala the second spike happened
uh past post-owner so that remains a
risk for us
um the only uh you know argument that
some experts are given i mean i'm not a
doctor or a people is so i can't comment
on this but what
some of the doctors are saying is that i
think the percentage of people who've
already
uh you know got in you know built
immunity
antibodies is much higher in india so
the risk is relatively low but i don't
think that's a
safe bet to have i think the risk of
some amount of spike is there in
april one question i'm getting from
bangladesh and the
gentleman asks uh what would be the
strategy for an insurance company to
make the demand of health insurance
coverage for
the pandemic like kobe 19. we had
initially an apprehension that
kovid is not covered pandemic is not
covered
uh the regulator and the insurance
industry came together to dispel that
doubt
maybe in bangladesh where you do not
have uh
indemnity-based uh health insurance
policy they have
all benefited based health insurance
policy maybe this
reservation or doubt comes from that
yeah
do you see that health insurance this is
the right time health insurance business
to take off
in a big way absolutely and it is taking
off so
you know like just to comment on the
gentleman's question
uh you know when the covert event
happened
none of us had knew about it none of us
had disappointed this right
uh so we will price for this but i think
as an industry
i am happy that we took a very
responsible stance that we will pay for
those games because if you get
hospitalized for any reason
on an indemnity policy we should pay for
it and you know
initially some there was some doubt
because i think one or two companies had
raised some doubts about it uh we had
clarified as i said
right in the beginning that we would pay
for those claims and the regulator also
said the same thing so that was good
uh because we've seen this in certain
countries because people have said
pandemic is not covered so we will not
pay for quoted covert claims
uh we believe that is not correct uh
it's come at a big cost for us as an
industry but
uh so be it that's why we are here so i
think i don't know if in bangladesh you
have
the same approach i have not studied it
uh but if you've
you know looked at the indian indian
industry our popular product which is as
professors is talking about the
indemnity product
which pays for which really indemnifies
the cost of
hospitalization those policies are
paying for uh covert
benefit policies are fixed benefit they
basically spell out
the diseases for which there will be a
payment so those policies don't cover
covert so they will not pay
but indemnity policies here in india are
paying for
this question data is the new fuel what
preparedness is
lombard adopting for the imminent
passing of data protection
act being a lawyer this is the question
to answer tough questions right yeah so
uh
you know obviously this is something
that we have to get up for
um we've studied the data protection act
and
we obviously have to ensure that we are
very transparent with our customers in
terms of
how we what data we take how we store it
and how we use it
uh our view is that you know it's a very
it's a very uh
kind of dichotomous world right at one
level people are very worried about
uh you know data you know personal uh
data
concerns um and equally they are very
open to share data i mean you see what
happens in
any social media today so our take is
out you know talking to customers is if
we are
able to give back something meaningful
something valuable using the data that
the customers
you know shares with us i don't think
and we don't misuse that that data
uh i think we are fine um
you know and customers are quite happy
to work with companies and that's
something that we have to
get used to so we have to think uh
creatively about
how do we use data in a meaningful
manner for customers
that's what we have to gear up for
another question coming from mr niles
satay as you all know mr satya was
member life insurance
he puts this question has there been
quantum jump
in cyber insurance post pandemic
everybody is asking that question hello
sir good to
uh you know chat with you even on this
platform uh
you know satay is a man that i think
nasty we have a lot of respect for
um so so honestly uh we've seen some
growth
a couple of companies a few companies
have launched retail cyber policies
and that's picking up in terms of
internal numbers
but as you know the base is very very
small and this is
uh even these increased growth numbers
are not going to move the overall
industry
you know gwp much but increasingly and
there's a lot of
effort that at least some of us are
taking in terms of education on cyber
side
there is clearly you know even even when
we are talking about smes we are seeing
some interest coming through in terms of
cyber and crime policies
uh corporates of course are much more
aware and increasingly we are seeing
some
interest in the retail segment as we are
launching retail products so it's just a
small segment it's growing but it's
uh our sense is that it's it's not yet
reached a meaningful proposed proportion
but the opportunity is large
uh may i also convey my sincere
gratitude to mr niles
he has been always very very supportive
to bimtech and
academics may i ask mr saket
if he wants to add something on data
protections
mr uh gupta in the beginning said if
any of this eminent panelists want to
add anything
uh mr ketan if you want to add something
on that
thanks dr chaturaj sorry to put you on a
spot on that absolutely not apologies
uh well uh i think you know there is the
eminent passing of
the data protection act in india and it
is
comparable and in some ways more
draconian than the gdpr
legislation we have in u.s yeah to my
mind businesses in india would need to
prepare
very carefully to the manner in which
data is managed
um in particular because the act
actually makes
a senior senior leadership team
accountable by making it a criminal
offense for breach
yes from an industry perspective which
means cyber
security response time as well as
in terms of protection all three needs
to be
ramped up so
the way i look at it is historically
uh as you mentioned indians don't
consider to be
considered data uh to be private
uh and therefore there is a dichotomy in
the indian economy
where everything is available and you
have an
act that is going to be passed which is
going to be making
uh the disclosure of data or the hacking
of data a criminal offense
so it's something that industry needs to
grapple with
and come to terms with and as you
mentioned as far as lombard is concerned
the protection of data and the real use
of data
becomes critical yes absolutely those
companies that
do that will actually you know
uh distinguish themselves uh from others
and that's where success will come yeah
you have to be responsible about it
it's it's significantly more challenging
because of the overall environment of
cyber we all
we are all obviously conscious of that
but it is
it is how you go about your intention
intentions is what will be important
absolutely thank you so much for joining
and
giving your valuable uh insight on that
particular matter
coming back to question uh mr dos gupta
uh one question is coming from a veteran
from bangladesh mr kazi muhammad murtaza
himself was a very well-known insurer
of this time his question is very simple
when insurers are paying more
claims less premium how can they invest
for advanced technology
so the answer is they can't so that's
why we keep saying
uh and i'll just give you an indian
statistic for the whole industry for
this body so if you look at the
indian industry's profit after tax
from 2008 to twenty right twelve years
uh you would expect i mean normally i'll
ask a question and ask for responses
which i can't hear i guess but
if you expect you would expect some
growth maybe you know five percent
compounded growth ten percent
what you'll be surprised to hear is that
the industry is de-grown by
if i remember the number correctly about
12 percent compounded
as in what we were earning as an
industry in 2008
was four or five times more than what
in fact today we are you know as an
industry we are kind of
lost making as an industry collective so
as an industry if you look at
in the year for 2020 the total profit
after tax for the industry was a minus
1400 crores but if you look at
four top four companies in terms of
profitability uh
the profits of the top four companies is
close to four thousand crores
right so that means that there are some
companies who are losing a lot of money
now those companies are not able to
invest in technology because you don't
you know that's the point that i made
that
you know if you think about running a
business you have to think of
all stakeholders including the
shareholder and you have to make money
because without that you can't
invest and forget investment i think the
bigger damage that that this does
is that you become very irresponsible
about even claims
because you're struggling to pay claims
because your cash flows
are being challenged so making some
reasonable profit
is absolutely important for investment
in distribution and technology in
penetration one of the reasons why i
believe penetration hasn't happened is
because we've not invested in
as a category as a as an insurance
category in terms of awareness creation
in terms of distribution into smaller
accounts
and that's largely because of very poor
underwriting that we've had
some of us have not been we've been much
much more cautious on quite a few
companies
and i think those are companies which
are able to invest in differences so i
think some question from the
budding youngsters who are going to
become the leaders in days to come
so one of my students asked this
question how has the analytics
enabled the leaders across the different
industries and geographies
to more effectively handle the
challenges present
presented by these unprecedented times
what role analytics is likely to play in
days to come
well it's absolutely valuable as i keep
saying that you know insurance is
probably the original data sciences
industry
right okay everyone talks about data and
data science but insurance was probably
originally the first
uh industry which used mathematical
models and looks and looked at data
we've kind of you know kind of uh
lost a bit of uh you know our computer
advantage in that sense from those days
but
uh i think that's the way to way to
think about you know
building your business in future so if
you
think about what i mean i'll just give
you a couple of examples so we talked
about this creating something meaningful
for customers using customer data
uh as an industry we've been very
transactional at a
product level today on a on a digital
platform maybe an app based platform
where customers are willing to
uh you know give their health risk
assessment give their
you know step count give the you know
kind of uh
you know uh wellness platform that
they're operating on or the
or their the behavior that they have in
terms of
taking care of you know exercising etc
you can use some of those data to
uh potentially give them some certain
benefits be it in terms of extra covers
or
you know some freebies here and there
etc and there are many companies in
globally who which have done that uh
coming to let's
say i talked about ai and ml uh today we
are able to do that i mean
as i said sixty percent of our health
claims we don't get a doctor to see the
claim
it's done through a machine learning
engine that we built over a couple of
years back
that's because of data of the past we've
used the data tree in the engine and
that's how the
engine operates today on a on a mobile
phone uh
say there is a you know breaking in your
auto insurance and normally we will
send a survey to check for damage
today we have a solution where you just
point your app at the damage you take a
few pictures
and the app you know using ai figures
whether there's a damage or not and
it tells you the process of the
insurance policy so those are
abilities that we've been able to build
because of data uh you know fraud i mean
we've
used our analytics engine an analytics
team to build a ml based fraud engine
which
improved our previous uh you know
solution that we had
by almost 10 points so every part of our
business
data is vital for uh for you know
creating the difference between you and
the next guy who doesn't use data
and that's how you will in a very highly
competitive industry that's how you
stay ahead of the curve
is virtual health likely to be the next
reality or next frontier
we you know we can't call ourselves
health experts but
if you study the sector from a
from a distance with a certain
perspective
you would argue yes if you see some of
the work that is happening
in digital health in in
particular in silicon valley i think it
will completely transform healthcare
our view is that in fact uh if you see
someone
talk to some of the experts there the
view is that
uh 10 15 years from now health will be
completely personalized
it will not be you know a standard
process
and the demand for hospitalization will
come down and it will be completely as i
said digitized and personalized and
customized help
based on your maybe your genetics or
your
activities or your you know the the the
small
you know what that will monitor
whichever way you want to call it
uh so our view is that it will be a
digitized health
model in the next 10 15 years whether it
will happen in that time i don't know
but
it will definitely happen in the near in
the future
my reason is that country like bhutan
bangladesh
if you look at the health
in this indexes index you will find
bangladesh and bhutan has better
uh life expectancy at birth what we call
lev
and that has not happened in india if
bhutan can do that and bangladesh
can do that and they they have been
using digital health
quite effectively my specific question
is how will the
healthy insurance industry respond to
that growing demand
for virtual health that's one and do you
think
things can also go the way that you
talked about silicon valley or
i'm talking about never next door bhutan
or bangladesh
is that likely to happen in india also
in days to come
so the problems for the two categories
are different and
my response was more for the set of
customers the top five ten percent of
the population who buys health insurance
goes to the top you know corporate
hospitals and you know i was
responding for that segment but even if
you look at
the uh the uh strata which doesn't get
proper healthcare
right and our traditional approach as a
country has been that
you have to have uh you know these uh
primary health centers
a doctor after his mbbs has to go to a
village and spend
you know two years of his or her time
and that's how you thought you'd provide
health care that's not work and that is
not going to work in future
but today you have the ability and the
technology to
provide healthcare at the doorsteps uh
in remote
india again using digital health
you can actually look at some of the
data and
so what you can do is have let's say an
asha worker
marginally trained using a tablet uh
with an ai engine behind or a virtual
doctor behind
which can provide the same level of
service in a village
and using that you can actually
aggregate data much better you can
figure out that there is an epidemic
that is
bubbling up in some small part of the
country
much earlier than uh in in the current
upwards that we have
so there is a huge opportunity if we can
actually leapfrog the
thought process on health using the
current technology that is
uh available and becoming available as
we speak
to transform health care and obviously
there's a huge need that we need to do
we need that we have as a country in
terms of doing that fast
right so asia has been quite a relation
and unfortunately in india
despite it being a great success story
we have not been
able to exploit their the kind of
services they have been given
particularly in the village in
kerala i have first-hand experience
interacting with
workers there so they have been doing
well and i i have a feeling
if the arthur experiment carried forward
can
transform the face of indian health
insurance
to a great extent the kind of gadgets
they are using the kind of data
you can gather yes will you
like to take some more questions if
i can take a couple of more questions
thank you so much something
all right sir uh
i have few questions coming uh
one question is some brokers that lack
i.t infrastructure
are now having more difficulty providing
administrative services
how renewable information is now
obtained and how are
using data assumptions to solve this
so uh some of this uh broken firm uh
the question if i understand properly is
that
uh they have administrative chart
because they
do not have id influx structure in place
so one is to get the it infrastructure
but even if they don't get it
how are they going to deal with it
look i i'll obviously have to understand
the problem more
clearly but even you know any
organization be it a broking or an
insurance company
as i keep saying unless you build some
of these capabilities
you run the risk of losing out in the
marketplace
if your customer is not getting a
service from you because you don't have
the
let's say digital capability and the
customer wants insurance
he or she will shift to some other
distributor and there will be other
distributors who will invest in
technology
so one of the things that we are happy
to do as icc lombard is actually happy
to work with distributors
in enabling them digitally and
technologically so that they can
actually continue to do their business
we see it as a win-win for our
distributor and our agent and that's
what
i mentioned that's the kind of point
that i've talked about when i talked
about hybrid
agency and similarly we've done for
small brokers
using some of our technology platforms
to allow them to
use them to sell policies but
you have to agree to use technology
without that it will become a
challenging future
another question is that why is it that
micro insurance or micro health
insurance not taking up in
india we have a very robust regulation
in place
and none of the neighboring countries
have that kind of regulation in place
despite the regulatory pro plotting
it has somehow not lived up to the
expectation of common public
micro health insurance is something that
can do wonders
going to the people who really need
health care more
as a rural people or the migrant
laborers
there are i think there are multiple
issues the regulator is
now thinking of setting up separate a
kind of a regulatory architecture for
micro health insurer micro
insurance companies with less capital
i'm not sure that is going to solve the
problem i think the problem has to be
understood at the root
in terms of what does the customer need
and are we able to provide that
in a manner which is commercially
valuable for everyone
uh and if you think about at the bottom
of the pyramid
we've done enough research we were
probably the early companies in terms
of some of these policies social
policies
back in 2006 14 15 we were very active
i think one of the clear learnings is
that at that level
people have other bodies insurance is
not the first thing that you
buy you know when you think of your
uh allocation of your monthly you know
budget there will be
certain things that will take priority
over insurance at that point
at that level of income and that's a
reality that you have to accept
and hence uh it is not as if uh someone
who's
uh at a level of substance subsistence
or barely making do
i think the first thing that they will
do when they earn a bit more
will be to buy some certain assets it
will not be to buy insurance
uh and hence uh i think the way
government is thinking about the
ayushmann
initiative is probably the way to go we
believe that's the right approach
that will address the bottom 40 50 of
the population we have to as an industry
and
policy makers come together to figure
out what happens to the next 40 because
the top 10 15 percent is covered through
retail and you know corporate
but the middle 80 middle 40 is what we
have to solve for
middle 40 is the real challenge
how exactly health insurance traveled to
them yes one last question
that i'll ask and it comes from a
student and he asked me this question
what according to you are the skills
that a fresher need to acquire
to have to have before entering the
insurance industry they are all two-year
insurance students there we have retail
program also we have the pgdm2
a two-year pgdm course and international
business
the four courses we run here and
believe it or not we were the first to
start insurance code professionally i
know
i know and that's what we started before
the nine year also
yeah that's what's special about wim
tech right so that's why we keep uh
looking at looking up to wiptec
so you know the one answer that i have
for anyone in any industry is
whichever industry you uh go in uh
first really understand the industry
understand whether what that industry
does
is appealing to you uh at the end of the
day your
value system system has to align you
know
every industry has its own purpose our
purpose is really to solve for the risk
needs of customers
if you find that interesting join the
industry if not find the industry that
you enjoy
and get excited by and join that
industry
now once you come in then it is all
about if you enjoy what you're doing
you'll find you know you'll find ways to
do well in that industry and at least
what we talk about uh in ics lombard is
uh
attitude is more important than skills
skills you can
you can get you can acquire attitude is
something that uh
you have to have so come in with an open
mind
with a with an approach to learn and
grow within the industry you'll do well
this is a techno marketing industry
right so we have to do the marketing of
course but it's a very
technical uh subject so you have to have
the
interest to and the willingness to learn
uh
and that's why i keep saying you have to
have the right attitude
and if you do that this is a very
exciting place
thank you so much sir for joining would
have loved to hear
you for hours but we will keep the time
lag 7 30 we wanted to end
and thank you so much in fact
it was one of the most interesting
sessions
we had we have
the ex-member of uh la member life
iida mr niles satya mr arun agrawal mr
saket ketan mr
and all our senior colleagues from
bimtech joined this
interesting discussion uh thank you so
much
my turn is over i request saloni senator
to take over from here
thank you so much uh dr chapter i think
the questions
were so relevant and we have drawn a lot
of sensibility
thank you uh doc mr for addressing each
of them
in such detail it's very encouraging i
thought
it's not easy for me to sum up uh what
you have said
so i was helped by dr
he's always mentoring me towards some
new knowledge so he shared a mckenzie
report which was released very recently
and it was an insurance resilience in a
rapidly changing corona various worlds
on page number three there was a
paragraph which says about resilience
and return
weathering the crisis so the benefit of
all i would like to refer to one
paragraph from that
because i thought it would add value so
uh it says given the uncertainty about
the duration of code 19
in individual markets a clear priority
is the development of contingencies for
the possibility of extended impact
including the potential for second and
third waves of the virus
building these contingencies requires
taking a hard
look at the initiatives that will
improve both
the use of resources and field
productivity
i think the story of icici lombard has
really
you know taught us a lot your
initiatives have guided many so at this
point of time
i think lori madam i will interrupt
we have three books uh one written by
professor k.k sina this is a book sir
we love to present you thank you
it's written by prof this is another
book
by the
rajan the third payloar sir
i'll request you to
honor mr das gupta with this book it's
not there with you sir
this is a very famous book by vivek
deybroy and
anirban grangoli and so this is third
book sir uh
mr ketan please do the honor and thank
you so much for
uh speaking to us uh it was just very
very
thank you thank you thank you my
pleasure my pleasure
yeah so this is a another big message
for all the aspirants here
uh read read read if you want to succeed
and you know therefore you have to just
pick up
anything and read so thank you uh so
much
uh professors for uh this moment
and the strong message in itself so at
this point of time i'm just reminded of
a certain sentence i read any
kind of crisis is good it wakes you up
so i think we all
are awakened today in ways so many
as an expression of gratitude i would
like to invite professor pratik
priyadarshi he is an associate professor
in the department here
in insurance department he's also
heading
to px program they're doing some great
work over there
so i invite him to present the vote
thank you salary man the the biggest
challenge for me right now is that
my chairperson has stolen my thunder and
uh
sir uh dr veda said i would formally
like
like to lodge a complaint
what happens is that after such an
enlightening talk such interesting
discussions
you know people are not interested in
listening to any other
talk that comes up their way but having
said that there are two things that i am
reminded of sir one
is that interestingly and and
coincidentally
this is the period where in the west we
call it the
thanksgiving week or thanksgiving day
and and and saket
answer would agree that this is the time
when families get together to say thanks
to the nature and to the almighty
for the gifts that they have been
bestowed upon we in india talk about it
in terms of makar sankranti and
and fungal and things like this but said
the mood question is that
why do we say thanks the important thing
is that
we acknowledge the support we help
and and and the the gratitude that we
show towards
your help that has made this trend a
successor
uh honestly speaking sir if we if you
were to take the
total number of questions that were put
across to you it would need at least six
more hours for this session to go on
and from that perspective i'm grateful
to the friends of bimtech
to my alumni and and to people
particularly
these industries are stalwart sir uh
people like mr bd banerjee
people like mr arun agrawal kkk mishraji
who was my
my boss in the public sector as also in
the private sector
and i had made a promise to him that i
would strive so that i live up to his
expectations
and then of course i would like to show
my gratitude
and express thanks to people like mr
nilesh satya
you know having a member of the
regulatory board guiding us
is an awesome experience for us and sir
that would explain to you
why we have someone like vidisha in your
organization
we have always strived and this was
initiated way back in 2000 when
dr chattawade thought about starting the
insurance business management
that we have reached a stage where we
can truly say
that the world is ours i would also like
to express my gratitude to the entire
iit team in particular to mr kapil gerk
of who made this entire arrangement a
flawless setup
so that we could have such easy
interactions i'm grateful to the people
who've come in from outside particularly
bangladesh the middle east and of course
nepal
we had we i i sincerely missed mr
sanjaya dutta at the
colloquium and now that he's here i
would just like to
let him go with a warning you know next
time better be there you know buddy
i look forward to asking some difficult
questions from you
but having having having said that sir
uh i'm
honestly speaking overwhelmed at the
fact that uh
you were able to spare almost two hours
of your valuable time
in having a discussion with the entire
lord and that we are here
uh so i would be failing in my duty if i
do not
talk about the most important aspect of
this entire
system that we have right now and that
is that the wake up call that you talked
about sir
i'm i'm really thankful to you that such
as a simple
message was communicated by you to the
entire lot of people who were
watching this in particularly to the
students
and and the alumni that we have this is
the career path that one should look
forward to
so uh on behalf of uh director bimtek on
behalf of bim tech and on my personal
behalf
uh our gratitude my thank you and and uh
good wishes to you
thanks thank you so much thank you for
having me thank you thank you
to
you